Guide to the Larry Polansky Papers MSS.405
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI. Personal, 1937-ongoing; 16.25 Linear Feet in 33 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, and 1 oversize flat box; 126 Gigabytes in 112,457 computer files.; 641 audiocassettes; 30 sound cassettes (dat); 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  This series contains Polansky's correspondence and subject files, personal audiocassette collection, clippings, groups of backed up computer files, and an archived version of his website. Polansky's correspondence and subject files comprise a large portion of the paper files in this series, containing correspondence with colleagues and friends within the modern music field, including Christian Wolff, James Tenney, Kenneth Gaburo, and Anita Feldman. These files also contain Polansky's subject and research files on specific composers, theories, and funding ideas. This series contains a significant number of clippings from the 1970s to the 2000s on Polansky and his work, including profiles, reviews of albums and performances, and his work with Frog Peak Music. This series also contains Polansky's regularly backed up computer files which remain grouped by the date of the backup. Files found within these backups range in date from the 1980s to the 2000s, including a mixture of both personal and professional files. Personal computer files include correspondence and calendar entries, while professional-related materials include album recording information, teaching-related material, and other projects. His archived website includes a complete list of his scores, audio recordings, and document files including writings and special projects. Polansky's personal audiocassette collection contains commercial and homemade recordings of work by friends and colleagues, many of which are not widely distributed. These recordings range in date from the 1970s to 2000s. Polansky's audition and college senior concert audio recordings from the late 1970s can also be found in this series.
  Files remain in their original alphabetical arrangement, most retaining their original file titles.
  The inventory lists either in an alphabetical range by title or listed individually if the title has more than one folder.
  Polansky's audiocassette collection is listed as Sound Recordings, retaining Polansky's original numbering system as part of the title. A list of the individual titles is located in the repository's donor file.
  The backed up groups of computer files were not individually sorted and arranged, but maintained by their backup date. Each grouping of files are titled according to the date of the back up.
  - A -- Always Move Towards the Hoop..., 1982-2011, undated; cuid25794 (Box 39, Folder 1-5)
  - Ames, Chuck, 1978, 1982-1993, undated; cuid25795 (Box 39, Folder 6-9)
  - Amiga A-D Converter -- Anti-Nuke Chain Letter, 1985-1987, undated; cuid25796 (Box 39, Folder 10-13)
  - Appleton: Moog Correspondence -- Belgium Gig by Tune's Dad Photographs, 1983-2012, undated; cuid25797 (Box 40, Folder 1-12)
  - Archived Website, 2015-ongoing; cuid25879 (Box Electronic Records, E-records https://wayback.archive-it.org/4049/*/http://eamusic.dartmouth.edu/~larry/)
    Accruals
    New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
    Archived Website Policies and Procedures
    Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
    Larry Polansky's website contains selected publications of his writings, his scores, computer software and programs, as well as documentation for his classes, including his American Sign Language Poetry class.
  - Audiocassette Collection -- #1-387, 1973-2000; cuid25854 (Box 85, Box 86, Box 87, Box 88, Box 89)
  - Audiocassette Collection -- #388-451, 1977-1996; cuid25855 (Box 90)
  - Audiocassette Collection -- #452-633, 1980-2000 (Box 91, Box 92, Box 93, Box 94)
    - #562 and #563 -- New Music Editions from Lou Harrison, cuid25935 (Box 92, Cassette 562, 563, Box Digitized Access Files, File MSS.405_cuid25935A, MSS.405_cuid25935B)
      Suite for clarinet and bassoon by Johanna Magdalena Beyer, transferred to audiocassette from the original 78rpm records by Lou Harrison in the 1980s.
      Total duration: 100 min.; Preservation note: There is significant surface noise from the original 78rpm discs that are inherent to the audiocassette recordings.
    - #574 -- "On Being Invisible, Part I" and "Music of Jon Hassell", 1976; cuid7070 (Box 91, Cassette 574, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss405_cuid7070)
      Original format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 74 min.
  - Benary, 1992-1993, undated; cuid25798 (Box 40, Folder 13-15)
  - Berkley Quick MQ -- Boros, 1937, 1984-2012, undated; cuid25799 (Box 40, Folder 16-21)
  - Boxing Day Apocrypha -- Brown, Chris, 1981- 2012, undated; cuid25800 (Box 41, Folder 1-4)
  - Brün, 1977-2012, undated; cuid25801 (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
  - Burk, 1986-1991; cuid25802 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Burt, 1981-2003, undated; cuid25803 (Box 41, Folder 8-9)
  - Buxton / Computer Music -- Cantillation / Torah Tropes, 1976-2012, undated; cuid25804 (Box 41, Folder 10-14)
  - Cemeti -- Philip Corner, 1961-2008, undated; cuid25805 (Box 42, Folder 1-11)
  - Clippings: KPFA, 1982-1990; cuid25741 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Clippings / Reviews, 1970s-2013; cuid25806 (Box 43, Folder 1-7, Box 74, Folder 7-8, Box 83, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence, 1976-2009; cuid25807 (Box 42, Folder 12-13)
  - Cowell, 1947-2012; cuid25808 (Box 42, Folder 14-15)
  - Crofts, Jamie -- Cuddy and Cohen, 1976, 1996, 1998; cuid25809 (Box 42, Folder 16-17, Box 83, Folder 6)
  - D, 1982-2012; cuid25810 (Box 42, Folder 18-19)
  - Dai: Paizto / Zipf Paper, circa 2006; cuid25811 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Didkovsky -- Diapason Press, 1984-2009; cuid25812 (Box 44, Folder 1-8)
  - Dodge, 1973-1994; cuid25813 (Box 44, Folder 9-10)
  - Doty -- Dowling, W.J., 1978-2002; cuid25814 (Box 44, Folder 11-12)
  - Dunn, 2004, undated; cuid25815 (Box 44, Folder 13-14)
  - E -- Feldman, Anita, 1981-2013, undated; cuid25816 (Box 44, Folder 15-19)
  - Feldman, David, undated; cuid25817 (Box 45, Folder 1-2, Box 83, Folder 7)
  - File Backup on 7/29/1997 (Files Created 1986-1997), cuid25916 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_47)
  - File Backup on 11/1997 (Files Created 1986-1997), cuid25912 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_43)
  - File Backup on 12/13/1998 (Files Created 1986-1998), cuid25913 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_44)
  - File Backup on 9/9/1999 (Files Created 1986-1999), cuid25918 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_49)
  - File Backup on 7/11/2000 and 8/18/2000 (Files Created 1986-1999), cuid25915 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_46)
  - File Backup on 9/2000 (Files Created 1980s-2000), cuid25917 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_48)
  - File Backup on 8/29/2003 (Files Created 1986-2003), cuid25914 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_45)
  - File Backup on 1/16/2011 (Files Created 1980s-2011), cuid25911 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_42)
  - Fink, M.J. -- G, 1949-2002, undated; cuid25818 (Box 45, Folder 3-7)
  - Gaburo, [Kenneth], 1984-2004, 2008; cuid25819 (Box 45, Folder 8-9)
  - Garland, 1977-2006, undated; cuid25820 (Box 45, Folder 10-12, Box 46, Folder 1-3)
  - Golden, B. Alive and Jesus... -- Grants, 1961-2009, undated; cuid25821 (Box 46, Folder 4-8)
  - Grayson: Sound Sculpture, 1976; cuid25822 (Box 46, Folder 9, Box 47, Folder 1)
  - H, 1982-2011; cuid25823 (Box 47, Folder 2-3)
  - Hadler: Indonesian Anti Semitism -- Joe Hickerson, 1971-2011, undated; cuid25824 (Box 47, Folder 4-9)
  - Horton, circa 1992, April 1994; cuid25825 (Box 47, Folder 10-11)
  - Intonation -- Ives, 1947, 1983, 2000-2010, undated; cuid25826 (Box 47, Folder 12-16)
  - J -- Tom Johnson, 1980-1990; cuid25827 (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - Johnston, Ben, 1960-1997; cuid25828 (Box 48, Folder 3-4)
  - Dan Junas -- Kennedy / Sounds Heard, 1981-2010; cuid25829 (Box 48, Folder 5-8)
  - Kitsz, Dennis, 1976-2007; cuid25830 (Box 48, Folder 9-11)
  - Knowles, Alison, 1998, undated; cuid25831 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - L -- Lowenberg, Richard, 1979-2012, undated; cuid25832 (Box 49, Folder 1-10)
  - M, 1965, 1978-2009; cuid25833 (Box 49, Folder 11-12)
  - MacDowell Colony Application, 2009, 2012; cuid25834 (Box 49, Folder 13-14)
  - Mahler, David, 1984-2013; cuid25835 (Box 49, Folder 15-16, Box 50, Folder 1-9)
  - Mann, Chris -- Music Through Midi, 1976-2008, undated; cuid25836 (Box 50, Folder 10-18)
  - N -- Pound, 1977-2009, undated; cuid25837 (Box 51, Folder 1-16)
  - Polansky Colleagues' Music Sound Recordings on Digital Audio Tape (DAT), 1988-2002; cuid25866 (Box 103)
  - Pritchett -- Rockmore, 1970s, 1981-2013; cuid25838 (Box 52, Folder 1-10)
  - Rosenboom, D., 1969-1987, 2007; cuid25839 (Box 52, Folder 11-12)
  - Rothenberg, undated; cuid25840 (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Rudhyar -- George Russell "River", 1966-1985, undated; cuid25841 (Box 53, Folder 3-5)
  - S, 1968-2010; cuid25842 (Box 53, Folder 6-8)
  - I Waygan Sadra -- Schoenberg, 1955-1999, undated; cuid25843 (Box 54, Folder 1-7)
  - Scholz, Carter, circa 1993, undated; cuid25844 (Box 54, Folder 8-10)
  - Seeger, Peggy -- Shaker Museum Letter, 1977-2000; cuid25845 (Box 54, Folder 11-16)
  - Shepard, Roger -- T, 1978-2011, undated; cuid25846 (Box 55, Folder 1-14)
  - Sign, Flute Lessons, undated; cuid25674 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Sound Recordings on Audiocassette -- Senior Recital, Auditions, and Colleagues' Music, 1977-2000; cuid25862 (Box 98, Box 99, Box 100)
  - Tenney, [James], 1969, undated; cuid25847 (Box 55, Folder 15-16)
  - Thanksgiving Booklet -- Barry Truax, 1975-1983, 2001, 2005; cuid25848 (Box 55, Folder 17-19)
  - Trubee, John -- Mike Winter, 1967-2010, undated; cuid25849 (Box 56, Folder 1-13)
  - Christian Wolff, 1964-2011; cuid25850 (Box 56, Folder 14-15)
  - Workshop on Matlab -- York University Class..., 1959-1997; cuid25851 (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
  - Young, Gayle, 1984-2004; cuid25852 (Box 57, Folder 4-5)
  - Zipf's Law Stuff -- Richard Zvonar, 1975-2005, undated; cuid25853 (Box 57, Folder 6-8)